LAID-BACK CAMP SEASON 3
Processed by 繁化姬 dict-121252ff-r1052 @ 2024/11/13 01:07:40 | https://zhconvert.org
OUTDOOR ACTIVITIES CLUB CLUBROOM
(野活会的房间)
THE PERFECT CUP OF COFFEE
(绝赞的一杯)
Making your own coffee while camping
一边露营一边泡咖啡
sounds cool.
总觉得很酷呢
I'd like to try it once in my life.
那是每个人都憧憬过的事呢
Please enjoy.
来 让你久等了
Why soba?
怎么是荞麦面啊
What's up, Aki?
小明 你怎么了?
As we all know, Lake Yamanaka looks like a roast chicken.
大家都知道 山中湖长得很像烤鸡
You made that up.
那是你自己乱说的吧
But actually,
但实际上
after investigating the other four lakes of the Fuji Five Lakes (Fuji Goko),
在我调查了富士五湖的 其他四个湖之后
I discovered something astonishing!
发现一件非常惊人的事
Lake Motosu looks like fried chicken!
本栖湖长得像炸鸡
Lake Shoji looks like a chicken wing!
精进湖长得像鸡翅
Western Lake looks like half a deep-fried chicken!
西湖长得像半只酥炸童子鸡
Lake Kawaguchi, on the other hand, looks like chicken with spicy sauce!
河口湖则是长得像口水鸡
That's right. It's even more apparent when you put them together!
没错 把它们摆在一起就更明显了
The shape of the Fuji Five Lakes!
富士五湖的形状
They all look like chicken dishes!
全都长得很像鸡肉料理
I think Lake Kawaguchi is a stretch…
不是 河口湖那个太牵强了吧
"FUJI CHICKEN GOKO" So from now on,
所以今后五湖应该 以"富士鸡五湖"为名
as "Fuji Chicken Goko," each offering its own local chicken dish
(富士鸡五湖) 推出每座湖特有的在地鸡肉料理
to boost the local economy!
让当地产业更加活络才对
Agreed!
赞成
I want to eat Lake Motosu fried chicken!
我想吃本栖湖炸鸡
All this talk about chicken is making me hungry.
一直讨论鸡肉的话题 害我都饿起来了
There are two types of campers.
听说露营客大致上分为两种人
There's the type that gains more equipment…
一种是随着露营的经验增加
What should I bring with me this time?
这次要带什么装备呢
Let's see…
我想想哦
Never mind.
算了
…the more they go camping.
装备越带越多的人
"MAXIMALIST CAMPER" I'll just bring everything.
(极繁主义露营客) 全都带去吧
This is too heavy.
这个太笨重了
Won't be needing this.
这个派不上用场
Or this.
这个也是
"MINIMALIST CAMPER" And the type that does the opposite.
(极简主义露营客) 以及越带越少的人
That does happen.
确实会发生这种事呢
The former ends up having
通常前者不久后
to drive a big car
就会因为带太多装备
to carry everything.
必须开大车载去
While the latter finds camping
而后者则会因为带太少装备
increasingly difficult due to too little gear.
导致露营的难易度变得越来越高
Gulp.
吞口水
Then, when they take to the extreme…
然后 做得太过火的两人
They end up like this!
最后肯定会变成这样
Let's bring everything!
全都带去吧
Maximalist Camper LV.100
极繁主义露营客LV.100
Minimalist Camper LV.100
极简主义露营客LV.100
I ought to be careful not to overdo it!
我也得小心别变成那样才行
Yeah.
对啊
There's no way that's going to happen.
不可能会变成那样吧
"HOME, ENA'S PLACE, MINOBU STATION, SCHOOL" Looks like
(我家 惠那家 身延站 学校) 这样看来
"RIN'S PLACE, HOTTODAKE HOT SPRINGS, BUDOU" I've still got a lot
(小凛家 别管我温泉 葡萄园?) 我对山梨还不算很了解呢
Nadeshiko's map of Yamanashi.
抚子画的山梨地图
It's too half-baked.
太粗糙了吧
She's only been here for half a year.
人家才搬过来半年而已
It can't be helped.
这也是没办法的事啊
That said,
话虽如此
she kind of got the gist.
但这里基本上就长这样呢
No… that Budou is way too big.
不…这葡萄园也太大片了吧
Her Yatsugatake area gobbled up a place or two or more too.
八岳区域还把好多地方都吃掉了
What about your map, Inuko?
那么 犬子的呢?
Mine…
我的嘛
looks something like this.
大概长这样
"CITY AREA, FRUITS AREA" Inuko's map
(都市区 水果区 住宅区 身延山区) 犬子画的山梨地图
Oh, yes, yes. This is it!
没错…就是这种感觉
"ENTRANCE TO SHIZUOKA" Since Nambu is close to Shizuoka,
(静冈的入口) 毕竟南部町离静冈很近
it does feel like an entrance.
确实有种入口的感觉呢
MT. FUJI
(富士山区)
I really hope I can live in the Mt. Fuji area someday!
真希望哪天可以 搬到富士山区住住看
"MINAMI-ALPS, HOT SPRINGS" Oh, right.
(南阿尔卑斯 温泉区) 对耶
There are many hot springs around the Minami-Alps area.
南阿尔卑斯那边确实有很多温泉呢
YATSUGATAKE
(八岳区)
I didn't know there were so many campsites in Yatsugatake.
原来八岳区有这么多露营场啊
ENTRANCE TO CHICHIBU
(秩父的入口)
The eastern side of the basin is far from Minobu,
盆地东侧离身延很远
so I don't know that area very well.
我就不太熟了呢
ENTRANCE TO SAGAMIHARA
(相模原的入口)
I want to visit there with everyone someday.
希望有天也可以 和大家一起去这附近玩呢
THE BIRTHPLACE OF THE INUYAMA CLAN
(犬山一族发祥地)
The birthplace of the Inuyama clan!?
犬山一族 发祥地
You found out, after all.
还是被你发现了吗
Well, you wrote it right there.
毕竟你都直接写在上面了
That is Shiotsu New Town,
那里是四方津新城区
near Kanagawa and Tokyo.
离神奈川和东京相当近
It's a satellite city built in Uenohara.
是一个建在上野原的卫星城市
It was also a ninja village
同时也是犬山一族
where the Inuyama clan lived until the end of the Sengoku period.
直到战国时代末期为止 居住的忍者村
A ninja village?
忍…忍者村
But after the Warring States period ended,
不过在战乱时代结束后
my clan decided to leave this land.
族人们决定离开这块土地
It is said that to never forget that this was where we originated,
据说为了不要忘记这里 是犬山一族的故乡
my ancestors shaped the mountain into the form of a dog
祖先们才会把山开拓成狗的形状
to remember this history.
留下来做纪念
When you put it like that, it does kind of look like a dog.
听…听你这么一说 好像是有点像狗
Later, houses were gradually built on this shaped land,
后来陆续有住宅盖在 这块开拓好的土地上
eventually forming Shiotsu New Town.
最后便形成了四方津新城区
How do you think Aoi came up with these stories?
小葵到底是什么时候 想出这些谎话的啊
Tall tales need to be surprising and realistic at the same time.
瞎扯话要同时兼具意外性和真实感
They should make everyone enjoy them,
还要努力让每个人都能乐在其中
and they must be
而且
the kind of stories that no one gets hurt even if they are fooled.
必须是那种就算受骗 也不会有人受伤的内容才行
It makes me cry just thinking about
一想到犬子可能每天晚上
Inuko writing down her tall tales passionately
都认真地在笔记本上 写下想到的瞎扯话
in her notebook every night!
我就快哭了
Let's just go along with it.
我们就乖乖上当吧
Let's allow ourselves to be fooled forever.
之后都乖乖被她骗吧